{
    "id": "5f4208c2c53d40feb206ce0469cddc4f",
    "title": "Simple Past Or Present Perfect Tense",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He ...................................... absent since Monday.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "83a66e8d5bf14ae5abbfbe334d74a879"
        },
        {
            "question": "Look. Somebody ......................................... their wallet on the table.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about recently finished actions and events.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "08f1160a18924fb0a8542a418c6b09c8"
        },
        {
            "question": "....................................... Janaki yesterday?",
            "description": "The present perfect cannot be used with past time expressions like yesterday.",
            "answers": [
                "Did you see",
                "Have you seen",
                "Do you see"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "99732e8633a84dafbc382ffc501fa2d2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I can't open the suitcase because I ........................................ the key.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about past events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "lost",
                "have lost",
                "had lost"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "99b4828e80a24484907c9249b279cdbc"
        },
        {
            "question": "Although I rang the bell six times, nobody ...................................... the door.",
            "description": "The past simple is used to talk about finished events that are in no way related to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "opened",
                "has opened",
                "had opened"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d34a83e75e6643bd9e9a94236acb8fd2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................. college last year.",
            "description": "The present perfect cannot be used with past time expressions like yesterday.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "have left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e74537609468451a8cb3aca3d0fcfa88"
        },
        {
            "question": "I never .......................................... my grandfather because he had died before I was born.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "had seen",
                "have seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b3498e9115fd4cb3b7a879539e19bf80"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the first time I ....................................... an opera.",
            "description": "The present perfect is common with the expression 'this is the first / second / last etc.'",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "have watched",
                "had watched"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c52c10b34d5d4a48abe527843ef67a9e"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can't see her now because she ........................................",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about past events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "already left",
                "has already left",
                "had already left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0a146b6499b4486694225987ca7ba8bb"
        },
        {
            "question": "He can't walk because he ....................................... his leg.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about past events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "broke",
                "has broken",
                "had broken"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "43aa9dde88794d30a82c98dc803a8970"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have known him since we ........................................ at university together.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "were",
                "had been",
                "have been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7ba9878b3c274bf1a94fbe389eee7bd3"
        },
        {
            "question": "It has been years since we ............................................ him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have met",
                "met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8d7853fe7e684a308cc8988b21ba64a4"
        }
    ]
}